ARMAGHAN NABI BEHLUM

PROJECTS

LesionPlot (Matlab) *July 2013*: Made to analyze the sizes of the lesions in the neurobiology lab where I worked. The program makes a plot of the entire brain or of each slice to show the damaged area.

RatSigs/Olveczky Lab Signatures (Java/Android/Python) *July 2013*: Application made to show how stereotyped human signatures are. Also developed for the lab where I worked, but as a presentation tool.

Mini-Mathematica (Python) May 2013: Implemented various matrix functions in ways that were faster or more interesting than their naïve and well-known implementations.

Laser Light Show (GWBasic) *June 2011*: Made a laser light show using mirrors, a laser, stepper motors, and some rewiring to printer ports. Wrote a program to write letters.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Languages: HTML/CSS/JS, Java, Android, Python, C, PHP, Matlab, Ocaml
- Applications/OS: Windows, Ubuntu/Linux, Git, Emacs, Microsoft Office
- Other: Computer hardware, soldering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSITANT FOR NEUROBIOLOGY- HARVARD UNIVERSITY

January 2012 - August 2013

Work involved brain surgeries on rats, removal of brains, and analysis of behavior and of brain damage. Summer work involved some programming as outlined in projects.

COURSE ASSITANT FOR MULTIVARIABLE CALCULUS - HARVARD UNIVERSITY

September 2012 - May 2013

Graded homework and lead 1 hour long weekly sections to review material

TEACHING FELLOW FOR INTRO TO COMPUTER SCIENCE - HARVARD UNIVERSITY

September 2013 - December 2013

Graded homework and lead 1.5 hour long weekly sections.

EDUCATION

SEWANHAKA HIGH SCHOOL

Graduated with High Honors and as Valedictorian.

HARVARD UNIVERSITY - B.A. IN APPLIED MATH WITH FOCUS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Cumulative GPA: 3.918 | Concentration GPA: 4.00